<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 | Elisa Macchi</title>
    <link>/publication-type/1/</link>
      <atom:link href="/publication-type/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>1</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>1</title>
      <link>/publication-type/1/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Graduate Student Mental Health Study</title>
      <link>/ongoing/econ-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ongoing/econ-mental-health/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worth your weight? Experimental evidence on the benefits of obesity in low-income countries.</title>
      <link>/jmp/job-market-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/jmp/job-market-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do visible wealth signals have instrumental benefits in low-information settings? I tackle this question experimentally by investigating the wealth signaling power and the instrumental economic benefits of obesity in the urban area of Kampala, Uganda. In low-resource contexts obesity is akin to a status good. Using photo-morphed pictures of real Kampala residents, I show that obesity is perceived as a strong and reliable wealth signal. To test for benefits, I cooperate with 124 small financial institutions in Kampala. In an incentivized field experiment I show that obese borrowers have easier access to credit, because loan officers exploit obesity as a wealth signal. Going from normal weight to obese improves access to credit as much as increasing one&amp;rsquo;s income by 60 percent. I pinpoint the mechanism by showing that reducing asymmetric information reduces the obesity premium by 70 percent.  Although loan officers appear to engage in statistical discrimination, I provide suggestive evidence that most loan officers hold biased beliefs about the income distribution by body mass. A final experiment shows that the benefits of obesity are commonly known, but generally overestimated. I discuss implication for anti-discrimination and obesity prevention policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-registration Experiment 1:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.socialscienceregistry.org/trials/4806&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.socialscienceregistry.org/trials/4806  &lt;/a&gt; \&lt;br&gt;
Pre-registration Experiment 2: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.socialscienceregistry.org/trials/4528&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.socialscienceregistry.org/trials/4528  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
