<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health economics | Elisa Macchi</title>
    <link>/tag/health-economics/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/health-economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>health economics</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>health economics</title>
      <link>/tag/health-economics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worth your weight? Experimental evidence on the benefits of obesity in low-income countries.</title>
      <link>/project/p1_job-market-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/p1_job-market-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT: In low-resource settings, where asymmetric information is widespread and verification technologiesare lacking, visible status goods may be exploited as cheap wealth screening devices. Obesity
is visible, and in most low- income countries has the characteristics of a status good. In this paper,
I test experimentally whether obesity has monetary benefits because it is exploited as a signal of
wealth. To explore benefits I focus on credit markets. I estimate the causal effect of obesity by
randomly assigning body mass using photo-morphed pictures in loan applications. The setting is
Kampala, Uganda. In a field experiment with 124 financial institutions, I show that going from normal
weight to obese improves access to credit as much as increasing one’s income by 60 percent. I
pinpoint the mechanism by showing that reducing asymmetric information reduces obesity benefits.
In terms of welfare consequences, a model of credit discrimination suggests that loan officers overrespond to obesity as compared to an unbiased discrimination benchmark. Further experimental
evidence shows that lay people anticipate and overestimate obesity benefits, leading to additional
demand distortions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
