<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elisa Macchi</title>
    <link>/author/elisa-macchi/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/elisa-macchi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Elisa Macchi</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Elisa Macchi</title>
      <link>/author/elisa-macchi/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worth your weight? Experimental evidence on the benefits of obesity in low-income countries.</title>
      <link>/publication/job-market-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/job-market-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper provides novel experimental evidence on the wealth-signaling value and associated financial benefits of obesity in a low-resource setting. My empirical strategy leverages two experiments, which randomly assign obesity using weight-manipulated portraits. First, I show that residents of Kampala (Uganda) perceive obesity as a reliable signal of wealth (vs other traits, such as beauty or health). Second, I show that the wealth-signaling value of obesity translates into financial benefits, namely easier access to credit. In a real-stake experiment with 124 Kampala credit institutions, I find that professional loan officers screen borrowers based on body mass. Obese borrowers have easier access to credit: moving from normal weight to obese is equivalent to increasing one&amp;rsquo;s income by 60%. I shed light on the mechanism by showing that reducing the asymmetric information strongly reduces the obesity premium. While these results are consistent with standard screening mechanisms, I also find suggestive evidence of deviations from the rational-expectations benchmark. Loan officers hold inaccurate beliefs about the borrowers&amp;rsquo; conditional income distribution by body mass, and appear to favor obese borrowers to an inefficient extent. On the borrowers&amp;rsquo; side, I show that obesity benefits are commonly known (and significantly overestimated). I discuss implications for credit provision and obesity prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Graduate Student Mental Health Study</title>
      <link>/ongoing/econ-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/ongoing/econ-mental-health/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pressure to employ, productivity and technology adoption: evidence from rural Uganda.</title>
      <link>/publication/norms-productivity-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/norms-productivity-tech/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Graduate Student Mental Health Study</title>
      <link>/publication/econ-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/econ-mental-health/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EU transfers and Euroscepticism: can’t buy me love?</title>
      <link>/publication/bmm_cant_buy_me_love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/bmm_cant_buy_me_love/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
